So, Robert can you talk a little bit about maybe advice that you would give to
Robert 你可以跟我们谈谈你自身受用的建议
yourself and also maybe like what keeps you going in the world of data science.
或者 你做数据科学的动力是什么吗
Yeah. Definitely, the number one thing that I recommend is just focus on
好当然 首先 我建议的是
the fundamentals and these are things like basic computing skills,
注重基础 比如基本的计算技巧
basic statistics knowledge, good analytical mindset,
统计学基础知识 清楚的分析思路
SQL, so and so forth.
SQL 等等
The second thing that I think it's very important is to look for a company
其次我认为找到一家
that is willing or has been investing in data engineering.
愿意或者已经在数据工程上投入的公司很重要
So, having a solid data infrastructure team,
有扎实的数据基础结构团队
having a solid engineering team,
扎实的工程团队
and have a reasonable data warehouse,
有合理的数据仓库
which you can extract data and play with the data.
得以提取数据和处理数据
My first job I was literally executing SQL script in tendon by
我的第一份工作是手动运行 SQL 脚本
hand to now we're using airflow and we can do
现在我们使用 Airflow (数据管道软件)
very sophisticated stuff and everything is automated.
可以实现非常复杂的功能 所有事务都可以自动化
So, there's definitely best practices that can be learned.
这是我能提供的最好的一些建议
So, it sounds like you're saying also for companies anyway, having data engineers,
好的 感觉你说的也适用于公司 有一个数据工程师团队
and figuring out what you want to store and
清楚希望保存什么数据
how it's going to be stored is like almost more important
清楚如何保存 好像更为重要
than bringing on data scientists who are supposed to tell you what to do
比拥有数据科学家团队重要
with data until you have a plan and you're storing the right things.
他们的角色是在你规划并且保存好数据后 告诉你应该如何使用数据
Yeah, I think the person who articulated this best is Monica Rogati.
是的 我认为关于这一点阐述得最好的是 Monica Rogati
She wrote also on media and she wrote a post called "The AI Hierarchial Needs."
她写一些媒体文章有一篇博客 名字是 AI的需求层次(The AI Hierarchial Needs)
She described how like basically analytics are build in layers
她描述了数据分析如何分成不同的层次
and you have to start from the foundation and
你必须从基本的需求开始
the foundation is like having your data infrastructure in place,
基本的需求像是 合理的数据基础架构
having your ETL in place,
合理的 ETL 管道
data warehouse and only after then can you do things like analytics,
数据仓库 之后才是分析之类的事务
experimentation, and machine learning.
做实验 还有 机器学习
I think that's very, very true.
我认为非常有道理
They always talk about after years of hard work finally,
人们总是说几年的汗水
they are able to achieve this,
终于实现了这些
but then they didn't really talk about of all the things that happened like before then.
但他们很少说道在那之前都经历了些什么
But that's really how any big and important data projects are built,
但这确实是任何大型的重要的数据项目的必经之路
it's layer upon layers.
逐层实现的